Register of the Donald Marquand Dozer Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- PANAMA CANAL FILE, 1901-1980
  - Interest groups
    - U.S. Congress
      - House of Representatives
        - General
          - Committees
            - Foreign Affairs (Folder 6)
              - General, Hearing transcript, agenda, 1973-1977.
              - Statements, 1967-1977
                - Derwinski, Edward J.
                - Dominguez, Jorge I., 1977
                - Dozer, Donald M. (SEE: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS FILE/, 1977 october)
                - Harman, Phillip, 1977
                - Mann, Thomas C., 1967
                - Moorer, Thomas H., 1977
                - Rousselot, John H., 1971
            - Merchant Marine
              - General, Memorandum/report by Terence W. Modglin relating to Panama Canal treaty negotiations and related matters, 1975 May 30; agenda, witness lists, 1975-1979. (Folder 7)
              - Correspondence, Includes letter from the committee to President Nixon, 1969-1979. (Folder 8)
              - Reports, Printed copies, 1968-1978. (Folder 9)
              - Statements (Folder 10-11)
                - Bunker, Ellsworth, 1977
                - Canal Zone Joint Labor Committee, 1969
                - DuVal, Miles, undated
                - Sullivan, Leonor, 1976
                - Tambs, Lewis A., circa 1977
        - Andrews, Ike, Letter to Dr. Dozer, 1977. (Folder 12)
        - Ashbrook, John M., Newsletters and form letter, 1975-1979. (Folder 13)
        - Aspin, Les, Letters, 1979. (Folder 14)
        - Bell, Alphonzo, Correspondence (includes a letter from the State Dept.), 1975. (Folder 15)
        - Brown, Clarence J., Letter to Dr. Dozer, and press releases, 1979. (Folder 16)
        - Crane, Philip M., Press releases, statements, serial issue, miscellany, letters to Dr. Dozer and others, 1973-1979. (Folder 17)
        - Derwinski, Edward J., Form letter, newsletter, 1974-1977. (Folder 18)
        - Dickinson, Bill, Newsletter and clipping, 1975-1977. (Folder 19)
        - Dornan, Robert K., Letter, 1978. (Folder 20)
        - Fascell, Dante, Letters, 1970-1971. (Folder 21)
        - Flood, Daniel J., 1963-1978
          - General. Press releases, memoranda, notes, biographical sketch (Box 76, Folder 1)
          - Correspondence
            - General, 1963-1978 (Folder 2-8)
            - Emergency Committee to Save the U.S. Canal Zone, 1966-1975 (Folder 9)
          - Speeches and writings, Mimeographed copies, printed articles, serial issues, 1964-1978. 1964-1978 (Folder 10-13)
        - Gross, H.R., Letters to Dr. Dozer, and a speech transcript, 1967-1973. (Folder 14)
        - Hansen, George, 1975-1979
          - General. Statement and press releases (Folder 15)
          - Correspondence. Primarily letters to constituents and colleagues (Folder 16)
        - Ketchum, William, Letter to ECSCZ, 1976 (Box 77, Folder 1)
        - Lagomarsino, Robert, Letters to ECSCZ and others (includes copies of statements) and press release, 1967-1978. (Folder 2)
        - Leggett, Robert L., Memorandum to Panama Canal Subcommittee members, 1973. (Folder 3)
        - Metcalfe, Ralph H., Letter to President Ford and a press release, 1975. (Folder 4)
        - Murphy, John M., 1971-1979
          - General. Press releases, speech transcripts, newsletters (Folder 5)
          - Correspondence. Includes letters to Dr. Dozer (Folder 6)
        - Pike, Otis G., Letters to ECSCZ, 1975. (Folder 7)
        - Rarick, John R., Letters (including a memorandum to George Wallace) and newsletters, 1969-1978. 1968-1978 (Folder 8)
        - Rousselot, John H., Letter, press release, 1973-1979. (Folder 9)
        - Rudd, Eldon, Correspondence, press release, 1977. (Folder 10)
        - Sabo, Martin O., Letter to Dr. Dozer, 1975. (Folder 11)
        - Simon, Paul, Letter to Dr. Dozer, 1979. (Folder 12)
        - Snyder, Gene, Correspondence, press releases, 1975-1977. (Folder 13)
        - Sullivan, Leonor K., Wire report, letters to Presidents Nixon and Ford, colleagues, and the ECSCZ, 1969-1976. (Folder 14)
        - Teague, Charles, Letters to ECSCZ, 1967-1973. (Folder 15)
      - Senate
        - General
          - General
            - General, Lists, wire report, pamphlet, 1976-1979. (Folder 16)
            - Amendments. Amendment sponsored by Robert Dole to the Panama Canal Treaty, 1977 september 22 (Folder 17)
            - Bills, 1968-1977 (Folder 18)
            - Resolutions, 1974-1975 (Folder 19)
          - Committees
            - Armed Services, Letters to Presidents Nixon and Ford, and colleagues, printed report, 1973-1978. (Folder 20)
            - Foreign relations, Press release and statements by Franklin Delano Lopez, Thomas H. Moorer, Maxwell D. Taylor, and Elmo R. Zumwalt, Jr., 1977. (Folder 21)
            - Judiciary, 1977
              - General. Agenda, letter to Dr. Dozer (Folder 22)
              - Statements
                - Bendetsen, Karl R. (Folder 23)
                - Canada, A. Joseph (Virginia State Senator)
                - Crowe, Guthrie F. (retired Canal Zone judge)
                - Dozer, Donald M. SEE: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS FILE/, 1977/July
                - Erickson, Ralph E. (attorney, Dept. of Justice)
                - Haar, Herbert R., Jr. (Assoc. Port Director, Port of New Orleans) (Folder 24)
                - Hansell, Herbert J. (State Dept. Legal Advisor)
                - Leonard, George S. (Attorney)
                - Lovelady, Rufus (American Federation of Government Employees)
                - McAuliffe, Lt. Gen. Dennis P.
                - McCain, Admiral John S., Jr.
                - Moorer, Admiral Thomas H.
                - Parfitt, H.R. (Governor, Canal Zone) (Folder 25)
                - Reagan, Ronald
                - Reynolds, Kitty L. (Women for Constitutional Government)
                - Rice, Charles E. (Prof. of Law, Notre Dame University)
                - Schwab, Donald H. (VFW)
                - Torrens, K.C. (Council of
                - American Master Mariners, Inc.)
              - Report. Printed copy (Folder 26)
        - Allen, James B., Press releases and statements, 1977. (Box 78, Folder 1)
        - Baker, Howard H., Jr., Letters, 1975. (Folder 2)
        - Bayh, Birch, Letters, including ECSCZ, 1975-1976. (Folder 3)
        - Brooke, Edward W., Letter to President Carter, 1978. (Folder 4)
        - Buckley, James, Letter to ECSCZ, 1976. (Folder 5)
        - Byrd, Harry F., Jr., Letter to ECSCZ, newsletter, press release, and statement, 1971-1978. (Folder 6)
        - Cotton, Norris, Letters to ECSCZ (includes letter from the State Dept.), 1973. (Folder 7)
        - Cranston, Alan, Form letter, press releases, 1978. (Folder 8)
        - DeConcini, Dennis, Letter to Dr. Dozer, 1977. (Folder 9)
        - Domenici, Pete V., Letter to Dr. Dozer, 1977. (Folder 10)
        - Dominick, Peter H., Letters, including ECSCZ, 1971. (Folder 11)
        - Ervin, Sam J., Jr., Letter to ECSCZ, 1975. (Folder 12)
        - Fannin, Paul, Letter, 1974. (Folder 13)
        - Garn, E.J., Form letters, letter to ECSCZ, 1977. (Folder 14)
        - Glenn, John, Form letter, circa 1978. (Folder 15)
        - Goldwater, Barry, Letter, 1974. (Folder 16)
        - Hartke, Vance, Letter to ECSCZ, mimeographed newspaper article, 1975-1976. (Folder 17)
        - Hatch, Orrin G., Form letter, undated (Folder 18)
        - Hatfield, Mark O., Newsletter, letter, 1977. (Folder 19)
        - Hayakawa, S.I., Newsletter, press releases, statements, letters, 1977-1979. (Folder 20)
        - Helms, Jesse, 1975-1979
          - General. Press releases, newsletter, memorandum and statements, 1975-1978 (Folder 21)
          - Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Folder 22)
        - Humphrey, Hubert H., Letters, 1975. (Folder 23)
        - Jackson, Henry M., Letters, 1977. (Folder 24)
        - Javits, Jacob K., Letter to ECSCZ, 1976. (Folder 25)
        - Kennedy, Robert F., Letter, 1967. (Folder 26)
        - Kuchel, Thomas H., Letter, 1966-1967. (Folder 27)
        - Laxalt, Paul, Letters, 1975-1978. (Folder 28)
        - Magnuson, Warren G., Letter, 1975. (Folder 29)
        - Mansfield, Mike, Letter, 1976. (Folder 30)
        - Mathias, Charles McC., Jr., Letters, including letter to Dr. Dozer, 1975-1977. (Folder 31)
        - McGovern, George, Letters and printed speech transcript, 1971-1976. (Folder 32)
        - Murphy, George, Letters, including letter to Dr. Dozer, 1966-1976. (Folder 33)
        - Percy, Charles H., Letters, including letter to ECSCZ, 1973-1978. (Folder 34)
        - Riegle, Donald W., Letter to Dr. Dozer, 1977. (Folder 35)
        - Schweiker, Richard S., Letter to ECSCZ, and press releases, 1976-1977. (Folder 36)
        - Scott, Hugh C., Typescript copy of a letter, 1976. (Folder 37)
        - Scott, William L., Letters, including ECSCZ, 1973-1978. (Folder 38)
        - Sparkman, John, Letters, including Dr. Dozer, and statement (wire report), 1976-1977. (Folder 39)
        - Stevenson, Adlai E., III, Letter, 1975. (Folder 40)
        - Stone, Richard, Clipping (mimeo) and letters, 1975-1978. (Folder 41)
        - Taft, Robert, Jr., Letters, including ECSCZ, 1975-1976. (Folder 42)
        - Talmadge, Herman, Letters, including ECSCZ, 1973-1977. (Folder 43)
        - Thurmond, Strom, 1967-1977
          - General. Newsletters and speech transcripts (Folder 44)
          - Correspondence, including ECSCZ and Dr. Dozer (Folder 45)
        - Tower, John G., Printed remarks, letters to Dr. Dozer, 1966-1972. (Folder 46)
        - Udall, Morris K., Letter, 1974. (Folder 47)
        - Weiker, Lowell, Letters, 1973-1976. (Folder 48)
        - Young, Milton, Letter to Dr. Dozer, 1977. (Folder 49)
- LATIN AMERICA SUBJECT FILE, 1910-1980
  Reports, memoranda, correspondence, clippings, conference materials, notes, speech transcripts, press releases, serial issues, pamphlets, flyers, newsletters, and other miscellany. Arranged by subject.
  - General
    - General (Box 78, Folder 50-51)
      - General (Non-printed material), Bibliography, speech transcript (Rigoberto Juarez-Paz), letter, and mimeographed reports, including "Report on the Liberty of Expression in America," "Restrictions on Freedom of the Press in the Americas," Harry Bernstein, "Free Minds in the Americas," Gerhard Masur, "Forms of Nationalism in Latin America," Arthur P. Whitaker, "Nationalism and Social Change in Latin America", 1943-1971.
      - Printed material
        - General, Report, statistical abstracts, bibliographies, and pamphlets, including Final Act of the Twelfth Meeting of the Inter-American Municipal Congress, and Agnes Nelms Lockwood, Indians of the Andes., 1956-1973. (Box 79, Folder 1-2)
        - Latin American studies publications. (Compilations of reports and studies by primarily academic groups), 1961-1980
          - General. Miscellaneous newsletters and serials (primarily in English)(E) (Folder 3-4)
          - Center for Latin American and Iberian Research Quarterly Report, Thunderbird Graduate School of International Management, 1971 (Folder 5)
          - Hemisphere Hotline Report, 1970-1980 (Folder 6)
          - El Informativo LASPAU (E)(S), 1970 (Folder 7)
          - The Kansas Latinamericanist, 1972-1973 (Folder 8)
          - Latin America, 1971-1976 (Folder 9)
          - Latin American Digest, 1966-1978 (Folder 10-11)
          - Latin American Report (same title used by two different organizations:)
            - Citizens Committee for a Free Cuba, Inc., 1967-1969 (Folder 12)
            - World Affairs Council of Northern California, 1974 (Folder 13)
          - Latinamericanist, 1969-1972 (Folder 14)
          - Pan American Headlines, 1966-1980 (Folder 15)
          - Times of the Americas, 1974-1979 (Folder 16)
      - Correspondence. (NOTE: Correspondence with citizens of specific countries or relating to those countries is located under national subject headings)
        - General
          - General. Family correspondence. Letters written by Dr. Dozer while traveling in Latin America
            - 1963 january-March (Box 80, Folder 1)
            - 1963 April-august (Folder 2)
            - 1965 June-september (Folder 3)
            - 1969 July-september (Folder 4)
          - Miscellaneous alphabetical, 1949-1980
            - Unidentified (Folder 5)
            - A-Z (Folder 6-14)
        - Blake, Robert, Includes short typescript report, 1960-1974. (Box 81, Folder 1-3)
        - Champlin, F.B., 1972-1975 (Folder 4)
        - Committee on Pan American Policy (John Birch Society). Correspondence with Harold Lord Varney; includes newsletters and flyer, 1964-1968 (Folder 5)
        - Hilton, Ronald (California Institute of International Studies), Includes a letter of introduction to Arturo Frondizi, 1959-1968. (Folder 6)
        - Lundy, Jack E., 1969-1970 (Folder 7)
        - Machado, Manuel, 1962-1975 (Folder 8-9)
        - Malek, Michael, 1971-1980 (Folder 10)
        - Mann, Thomas, 1966 (Folder 11)
        - Pacific Coast Council of Latin American Studies, 1964-1976 (Folder 12)
        - Peters, William, 1964-1967 (Folder 13)
        - Powell, Philip, 1959-1968 (Folder 14)
        - Tambs, Lewis, 1963-1980 (Folder 15)
        - Wolff, Thomas, 1959-1978 (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - Notes and business cards. Relates to Dr. Dozer's research trips in Latin America
        - General. Includes appointment book, 1963 (Folder 2-3)
        - Argentina (Folder 4)
        - Bolivia (Folder 5)
        - Brazil (Folder 6)
        - Chile (Folder 7)
        - Colombia (Folder 8)
        - Ecuador (Folder 9)
        - Paraguay (Folder 10)
        - Peru (Folder 11)
        - Uruguay (Folder 12)
        - Venezuela (Folder 13)
    - Culture
      - General, Bibliographies, printed article, flyers, reprint, clipping, pamphlets, mimeographed reports and printed booklets, includings Rene L.-F. Durand, La Negritude dans l'Oeuvre Poetique de Ruben Dario and Jorge Carrera Andrade, Livre de l'Exil Precede de Message a l'Afrique, 1941-1979. (Box 83, Folder 1-3)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1978 (Folder 4)
    - Demographics and population. Statistical charts, notice, printed and mimeographed reports including the State Department Office of Intelligence Research, "Population Growth and Economic Development in Latin America," the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, Population and the Role of Law in the Americas, Bryan Roberts and Stella Lowder, Urban Population Growth and Migration in Latin America: Two Case Studies, General Electric Technical Military Planning Operation (TEMPO), The Demography of South America--1975., 1949-1975 (Folder 5-6)
    - Economics
      - General
        - General
          - General
            - Non-printed material, Speech transcripts and curriculum vitae of William Simon in Spanish (S), and mimeographed reports including Hector Correa, "Sources of Economic Growth in Latin America," Fernando Chaves Nunez, "The Cooperative Movement in Latin America, "Latin American Consensus of Vina del Mar," and "The Pan American Highway System", 1950-1979. (Folder 7-8)
            - Printed material, Newsletter reports, pamphlets, bibliography, printed article (S), 1951-1978. (Folder 9)
          - American Chambers of Commerce in Latin America (AACCLA). Newsletters, 1971-1979 (Folder 10)
          - Pan American Development Foundation. Newsletters and annual report, 1968-1970 (Folder 11)
        - Correspondence, Includes a mimeographed paper by David Ambrose, "A Study of Marketing Fish Protein Concentrate Enriched Products for Preschool Children in Latin America"., 1950-1979. (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - Agriculture
        - General, Printed and mimeographed reports, pamphlets, speech transcript (John F. Gallagher), 1956-1969. (Folder 2-4)
        - Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agricolas (IICA)
          - General, Pamphlet, printed reports, and a mimeographed report by Armando Samper, "Contribucion de la Agricultura al Crecimiento Economico", 1967-1969. (Folder 5-6)
          - Newsletter, 1968-1972 (Folder 7)
      - Banks and banking
        - General, Serial issues and newsletters, 1944-1978. (Folder 8)
        - Inter-American Development Bank
          - General, Mimeographed reports, printed pamphlets, miscellaneous newsletters, 1960-1974. (Folder 9)
          - Correspondence, 1963-1975 (Folder 10)
          - Newsletter (IDB News), 1974-1980 (Folder 11)
      - Business
        - General
          - General. Newsletter and an annual report (Cerro Corp.), 1968-1977 (Folder 12)
          - Center for Advanced Studies in International Business. Conference materials, correspondence, pamphlets, newsletter, 1969-1973 (Box 85, Folder 1)
        - United States
          - Sears, Roebuck and Co. Pamphlets and speech transcript (John F. Gallgher, V.P.), 1966 (Folder 2)
          - United Fruit Company. Pamphlets, letters, speech transcript (John M. Fox, Pres.), reports, including Davis J. Cloward, "Schools in Bananaland: The Role of the United Fruit Company in Education in Middle America," and Harvey W. Johnson, "An Era of Mutual Progress: The Interdependence of United States Multinational Companies and Latin American Host Nations,", 1962-1976 (Folder 3-4)
      - Commerce
        - General. Letter, copy of the Trade Act of speech transcript (Anthony M. Solomon, State Dept.) and a printed report by Ramon P. Diaz, The Long Run Terms of Trade of Primary Producing Countries, 1974, 1965-1976 (Folder 5)
        - Inter-American Commercial Arbitration Commission. Report, printed articles and newsletters, 1969-1976 (Folder 6)
      - Economic aid
        - General
          - General, Press release, mimeographed report by John Eriksson, "Trends in the Volume and Composition of Aid to Latin America", 1964-1976. (Folder 7)
          - Alliance for Progress
            - General. Newsletters, poster, minutes, printed article, clippings (E)(S), notes, a pamphlet by Arturo Frondizi, La Alianza para el Progreso, and mimeographed reports by Carlos Vial E., "Necesidad de una Moralidad Internacional," and R. Harrison Wagner, "Explaining and Judging United States-Latin America Policies: A Framework for Understanding the Alliance for Progress", 1962-1973 (Folder 8)
            - Correspondence, 1962-1968 (Folder 9)
            - Speeches and statements
              - Richard Goodwin (State Dept.), 1962 March 16 (Folder 10)
              - Lyndon B. Johnson, 1963 March 20
              - John F. Kennedy, 1963 november 18
              - Carlos Urrutia-Aparicio, 1963 december 4
              - Carlos Sanz de Santamaria, 1964 March 16
              - Lyndon B. Johnson, 1964 May 11
              - Alberto Lleras, 1964 May 20
              - Lyndon B. Johnson, 1965 august 17 (Folder 11)
              - Jack H. Vaughn (State Dept.), 1965 september 10
              - Robert F. Kennedy, 1966 May 9-10
              - Lincoln Gordon (State Dept.), 1966 June 1
              - Lyndon B. Johnson, 1966 august 17
              - Lyndon B. Johnson, 1969 january 27
        - United States. Statistical charts and reports, pamphlet, correspondence, seminar proceedings, printed articles, 1957-1974 (Box 86, Folder 1-3)
      - Economic development
        - General
          - General, Newsletter, clippings, pamphlet, letter, speech transcript (William M. Dyal, Jr.), printed reports, including the International Development Advisory Board, An Economic Program for the Americas, and mimeographed reports, including Roger E. Vekemans, "Economic Development, Social Change and Cultural Mutation in Latin America", 1954-1978. (Folder 4-6)
          - Conference proceedings: "Seminario Sobre Desarollo Economico, Secularizacion y Evolucion Politica, Buenos Aires, Mimeographed reports (S), May 1963. (Folder 7)
        - Rio Bermejo Project
          - General, Certificates, contract, address list, map, clipping, statements of purpose, newsletter, pamphlet, resolutions, River Plate Basin Treaty text, 1961-1979. (Folder 8)
          - Correspondence (S)(E)(Polish). Includes letters to President Johnson, and correspondence with the International Development Bank (Antonio Casas-Gonzalez), Juan Carlos Ongania, the Polish PanAmerican Chamber of Comerce, Stanford Research Institute, Emilio Eduardo Massera, Arleigh Burke, Gov. Ronald Reagan, and others, 1964-1979 (Folder 9)
          - Notes and miscellany. Notes and business cards (Folder 10)
          - Reports and proposals
            - "Aprovechamiento Fluvial," by Nicolas Boscovich. Printed article, undated (Folder 11)
            - "Bermejo River Basic Multiple Development Project," by la Republica Argentina. Mimeographed report, 1964 March
            - "The Bermejo River Project," by the Bermejo Development Corporation. Mimeographed report, undated
            - "Obras de Desarollo Fluvial Multiple del Rio Bermejo: (Folder 12)
              - Estudio de la Factibilidad y Analisis de la Solidez Economica y Tecnica", 1963 May
              - Su Plan General de Obras y su Plan de Financiacion,", 1964 July
            - "Review of Planning for the Bermejo Region of Argentina," by the Stanford Research Institute, circa 1976
      - Economic history. Annotated bibliography, 1973 (Box 87, Folder 1)
      - Economic integration
        - General, Mimeographed reports and pamphlet, 1969-1972. (Folder 2)
        - Conference on Economic Integration of Latin America, sponsored by the California Institute of International Studies, Stanford University, 1968 May 9-13.
          - General. Conference materials, memorandum, speech transcript (David Rockefeller), pamphlets and agenda, 1967-1968 (Folder 3)
          - Reports (arranged alphabetically by author) (Folder 4-10)
      - Economic planning. Newsletter and a mimeographed report by Fernando Guillen Martinez, "Comparative Analysis of Planning in Different Types of Societies,", 1964-1970 (Folder 11)
      - Employment. Mimeographed reports by Zygmunt Slawinski, 1967-1969 (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Industry. Mimeographed report by Zygmunt Slawinski, 1954 (Folder 2)
      - Investment
        - General, Letter, newsletter and reports including the Rand Corporation, The Course of United States Private Investment in Latin America since the Rise of Castro, and the Council for Latin America, The Effects of United States and other Foreign Investment in Latin America, 1964-1970. (Folder 3)
        - Atlantic Community Development Group for Latin America (ADELA)
          - General, Press release, letters, resolutions, memorandum, conference materials, proposals, 1963-1964. (Folder 4)
          - Newsletters, 1974-1975 (Folder 5)
          - Reports, 1974 (Folder 6)
    - Education
      - General, Relates primarily to exchange programs and overseas schools. Memoranda, conference report, letter, information bulletins, flyers, 1957-1966. (Folder 7)
      - Latin American educational systems. Printed article, flyer, speech transcripts, printed reports by John P. Harrison, The University versus National Development in Spanish America, and General Electric (TEMPO), Changing Patterns of Education in Latin America (includes correspondence), and mimeographed reports entitled "Estadisticas del Analfabetismo," "The Spanish American University and the University Student," Roberto Munizaga Aguirre, "La Universidad Latinoamericana," Gonzalo Aguirre Beltran, "Organization and Structure of Latin American Universities with Reference to Economic Development," Harry Bernstein, "Cold War in the Curriculum," United States National Students Association, Latin American Student Affairs, 1960-1974 (Folder 8-10)